Guide to the Chih H. Wang Papers 1947-1984
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
- Training and Education Project Records, 1958-1981; Series III
  - TaiPower Reports and Publications, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 17.10)
  - TaiPower Reports and Publications, 1970 (Box-folder 18.1)
  - TaiPower Chinshan Unit #1 Review, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 18.2)
  - TaiPower Personnel Visits, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 18.3)
  - Tsing Hua University-TaiPower Training Program Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 18.4)
  - U.S. AEC Nuclear Science and Engineering Fellowship Advisers Meeting Records, 1964 (Box-folder 18.5)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, General Administrative Records, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 18.6)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, General Administrative Records, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 18.7)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, General Administrative Records, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 19.1)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, General Administrative Records, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 19.2)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, General Administrative Records, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 19.3)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, General Administrative Records, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 19.4)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, General Administrative Records, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 19.5)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, General Administrative Records, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 19.6)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, Final Reports, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 20.1)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, Budgetary Records, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 20.2)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, AEC Administrative Forms and Documentation, circa 1970 (Box-folder 20.3)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, Participant Records, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 20.4)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, Participant Records, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 20.5)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, Participant Records, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 20.6)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, Participant Records, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 20.7)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, Inquiry Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 21.1)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, Inquiry Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 21.2)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, Joint Directory of Higher Education Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 21.3)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "The Academic Year Institute...." AT(45-1)-2018, General Correspondence, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 21.4)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "Summer Workshop on Electric Power Generation: Comparative Costs and Benefits (1972)," AT(45-1)-2227, Administrative Records, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 21.5)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "Summer Workshop on Electric Power Generation: Comparative Costs and Benefits (1972)," AT(45-1)-2227, Course Materials (Box-folder 21.6)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "Electric Power Generation: Comparative Risks and Benefits (1972)" AT(45-1)-2227, Proceedings (Box-folder 22.1)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "Summer Workshop on Electric Power Generation: Comparative Costs and Benefits (1973)," AT(45-1)-2227, Administrative Records, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 22.2)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "Summer Workshop on Electric Power Generation: Comparative Costs and Benefits (1973)," AT(45-1)-2227, Course Materials (Box-folder 22.3)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "Summer Workshop on Electric Power Generation: Comparative Costs and Benefits (1973)," AT(45-1)-2227, Selected Readings (Box-folder 22.4)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "Summer Workshop on Electric Power Generation: Comparative Costs and Benefits (1973-1972)," AT(45-1)-2227, Proceedings (Box-folder 22.5)
  - U.S. AEC Contract: "Summer Workshop on Electric Power Generation: Comparative Costs and Benefits (1974)," AT(45-1)-2227, Administrative Records, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 23.1)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1975)," AT(45-1)-2227, Proposal (Box-folder 23.2)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1975)," AT(45-1)-2227, Newsclippings (Box-folder 23.3)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1975)," AT(45-1)-2227, Television Special Script (Box-folder 23.4)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1975)," AT(45-1)-2227, General Administrative Records (Box-folder 23.5)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, General Administrative Records, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 23.6)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, General Administrative Records (Box-folder 23.7)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 24.1)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Participant Correspondence (Box-folder 24.2)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Politician Invitation Letters (Box-folder 24.3)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Environmental Groups Invitation Letters (Box-folder 24.4)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Faculty and Speakers (Blood-Frisbee), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 24.5)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Faculty and Speakers(Goranson-Wang), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 24.6)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Final Exam (Box-folder 24.7)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Recreational Activities (Box-folder 24.8)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Course Materials (Box-folder 25.1)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Course Materials (Box-folder 25.2)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Evaluations (Box-folder 25.3)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Evaluations from Non-Paid Participants (Box-folder 25.4)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1976)," AT(45-1)-2227, Final Report (Box-folder 25.5)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Summer Workshop on Energy Resources and Electric Power Generation (1977)," AT(45-1)-2227, Proposal and Rejection, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 25.6)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Magnitude & Deployment Schedule of Energy Resources Conference (1975)," E(45-1)-2415, General Administrative Records, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 25.7)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Magnitude & Deployment Schedule of Energy Resources Conference (1975)," E(45-1)-2415, General Administrative Records, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 25.8)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Magnitude & Deployment Schedule of Energy Resources Conference (1975)," E(45-1)-2415, Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 26.1)
  - U.S. ERDA Contract: "Magnitude & Deployment Schedule of Energy Resources Conference (1975)," E(45-1)-2415, Proceedings (Box-folder 26.2)
  - Non-OSU ERDA Grant-Funded Publications, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 26.3)
  - U.S. AEC Grant Proposal: "AEC Traineeships for Graduate Students in Nuclear Engineering", 1969 (Box-folder 26.4)
  - U.S. AEC Grant Proposal: "AEC Special Fellowship Program in Nuclear Science and Engineering", 1969 (Box-folder 26.5)
  - U.S. AEC Grant Proposal: "Nuclear Engineering Program in Fuel Reprocessing", 1970 (Box-folder 26.6)
  - U.S. Department of Energy Faculty Development Projects in Energy Education, 1980 (Box-folder 26.7)
  - Washington Public Power Supply System Reactor Operator Training Proposal, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 26.8)
  - National Science Board Northwest Regional Forum, 1976 (Box-folder 26.9)
  - Nuclear Energy Forum, 1975 (Box-folder 26.10)
  - Nuclear Technology in Developing Countries Conference, 1981 (Box-folder 27.1)
  - MS Thesis: "A Comparative Study of the Carbohydrate Catabolism in Pseudomonadacea Microorganisms," Solveig Hjordis Bjerre, 1960 (Box-folder 27.2)
  - MS Thesis: "The Effect of 2-Deoxyglucose on Hexose Metabolism in Saccharomyces Cerevisae," Charles Wayland Conrad, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 27.3)
  - MS Thesis: "The Biosynthetic Precursor of Ethylene in Penicillium Digitatum Saccardo," Donald W. Jacobsen, 1965 (Box-folder 27.4)
  - MS Thesis: "Argon-41 Production by the OSU TRIGA III Reactor," Robert A. Merck, 1967 (Box-folder 27.5)
  - MS Thesis: "Comparative Carbohydrate Catabolism in Chromobacterium Species, Carol M. Wehr, 1969 (Box-folder 27.6)
  - Ph.D. Thesis: "Glucose Catabloism in Mung Bean (Phaseolus Aureus) Seedlings," George J. Ikeda, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 27.7)
  - Ph.D. Thesis: "The Estimation of Glucose Pathways in Saccharomyces Cerevisiae by the Catabolic Rate," Donald W. Jacobsen, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 28.1)
  - Ph.D. Thesis: "The Fate of Fluoride and the Effect of Fluoride Upon Glucose Metabolism in Intact Rats," Ronald M. Knaus, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 28.2)
  - Ph.D. Thesis: "Alterations of Carbohydrate Metabolism by Pentachlorophenol in Cichlid Fish," David H. K. Liu, 1969 (Box-folder 28.3)
  - Ph.D. Thesis: "The Effects of X-Irradiation on Metabolism of Glucose in the Intact Rat," Darrell L. Marks, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 28.4)
  - Ph.D. Thesis: "Rate of Catabolic Pathways of Glucose in the Intact Rat," John R. Prince, 1969 (Box-folder 28.5)
  - Ph.D. Thesis: "Radiotracer Studies of Carbohydrate Catabolism in Tomato Fruit," John C. Ramsey, 1964 (Box-folder 28.6)
  - Ph.D. Thesis: "Comparative Metabolism of Carbohydrates in Pseudomonads," Ivan J. Stern, 1958 (Box-folder 28.7)
  - Ph.D. Thesis: "The Role of Some of the Krebs Cycle Reactions in the Biosynthetic Functions of Thiobacillus Thiparus," Gerald G. Still, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 28.8)
  - Ph.D. Thesis: "Radiolysis of Succinic Acid in Water," Fred S. Tanaka, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 29.1)
  - Ph.D. Thesis: "Glucose Catabolism in Normal and Fluoride Injured Mung Bean (Phaeolus Aureus) Seedlings," Gerald E. Young, 1969 (Box-folder 29.2)
- OSU Radiation Center Administrative Records, 1950-1984; Series IV
  Series IV is composed of materials relating to the creation and operation of the OSU Radiation Center between 1960 and 1984. Materials include administrative reports, a procedural manual, a hazard analysis report, budgetary records, research and proposals relating to the Radiation Center facilities, records of tours, site visits, and inspections, classified document handling records and regulations, and questionnaires relating to nuclear science and engineering. Some materials in Series IV predate but relate to the Radiation Center mission and activities.
  - OSU Division of Radiochemistry and Radiation Chemistry Establishment and History, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 29.3)
  - OSU Radiation Center Descriptions and Fact Sheet, 1977-1983 (Box-folder 29.4)
  - OSU Radiation Center Progress Reports, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 29.5)
  - Report to OSU Vice President, 1978 (Box-folder 29.6)
  - OSU Radiation Center Standard Practice Procedures Manual, 1968 (Box-folder 29.7)
  - OSU Radiation Center Service Activities, 1978 (Box-folder 29.8)
  - OSU TRIGA Reactor Hazard Analysis Report Correspondence, 1965 (Box-folder 29.9)
  - OSU Radiation Center Affirmative Action Policies, 1971-1984 (Box-folder 29.10)
  - OSU Radiation Center Budget, 1975-1984 (Box-folder 29.11)
  - OSU Cost Sharing Policies, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 29.12)
  - OSU Radiation Center Full Cost Accounting, 1963-1981 (Box-folder 29.13)
  - OSU Radiation Center Construction and Initial Operating Budgets, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 29.14)
  - Sources of Funding for Instruction Programs in Nuclear Technology, 1960 (Box-folder 29.15)
  - OSU Nuclear Power Plant Proposal and Research, 1968 (Box-folder 29.16)
  - OSU Radiation Center Bench Surface Testing, 1962 (Box-folder 30.1)
  - OSU Radiation Center Concrete Compression Testing, 1966 (Box-folder 30.2)
  - Donation of Cesium-137 Source from Gunderson Brothers Engineering, Inc., 1963 (Box-folder 30.3)
  - Site Visits to Non-OSU Reactors, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 30.4)
  - Electronic Associates, Inc. Patent Infringement Lawsuit, 1977 (Box-folder 30.5)
  - OSU Radiation Center Tours, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 30.6)
  - OSU Radiation Center Tours, 1970-1984 (Box-folder 30.7)
  - NIH Site Visit, 1963 (Box-folder 30.8)
  - NSF Site Visits, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 30.9)
  - OSU Radiation Center Classified Document Records, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 30.10)
  - U.S. AEC Regulations and Reporting Guidelines, 1950-1974 (Box-folder 31.1)
  - AEC "Standard Format and Content of Safety Analysis Reports for Nuclear Power Plants", 1971-1972 (Box-folder 31.2)
  - U.S. Department of Defense Industrial Security Manuals, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 31.3)
  - U.S. Department of Defense Industrial Security Manual, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 31.4)
  - U.S. Defense Documentation Center Correspondence and Regulations, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 31.5)
  - Surveys and Questionnaires re: Nuclear Science Technology and Instruction, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 32.1)
  - NSF-ORU Questionnaire, 1981 (Box-folder 32.2)
  - Westat/NSF Instrumentation Survey, 1983 (Box-folder 32.3)
- Publications, 1947-1972; Series V
  Series V contains reprints and abstracts of publications authored by Chih H. Wang during his tenure with the OSU Chemistry Department and the Radiation Center. Topics include organic chemistry, biochemistry, radiochemistry, radiation physics, nuclear engineering, and education. Many of the papers in this series were coauthored with members of the OSU faculty--especially Bert E. Christensen, Vernon H. Cheldelin, Donald J. Reed, and Frank N. Dost. Topics include "The Influence of Molybdates on the Hydrogen and Peroxide Oxidation of Naphthalene and Beta-Naphthol," "Coordinated Design of Radioisotope Laboratories, and "Studies on Environmental Pollution by Missile Propellants."
  - Article Offprints, Reprints, and Abstracts, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 32.4)
  - Article Offprints, Reprints, and Abstracts, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 32.5)
  - Article Offprints, Reprints, and Abstracts, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 32.6)
  - Article Offprints, Reprints, and Abstracts, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 32.7)
  - Article Offprints, Reprints, and Abstracts, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 32.8)
  - Article Offprints, Reprints, and Abstracts, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 32.9)
  - Article Offprints, Reprints, and Abstracts, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 33.1)
  - Article Offprints, Reprints, and Abstracts, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 33.2)
  - Article Offprints, Reprints, and Abstracts, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 33.3)
  - "The Role of a Nuclear Engineering Technology Curriculum in the Nuclear Power Era", circa 1972 (Box-folder 33.4)
  - Article Review for Publishers, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 33.5)
- Subject Files, 1949-1980; Series VI
  Series VI is comprised of subject files assembled by Chih Wang. Included in the series are scientific offprints, promotional materials, reports, newsclippings, notes, and a small amount of correspondence. Topics include biochemical experiment design and techniques, microorganism behavior and functions, biological systems, radiation physics and uranium recovery, and public opinion and legislation regarding nuclear power in California, Oregon, and Washington. The series also contains materials, including a full script, related to the 1977 television movie Red Alert and correspondence regarding Energy Resources--How Much, How Soon, a film comprised of highlights from a 1975 conference at OSU.
  - Biochemistry and Biophysics Experimental Techniques, 1949-1961 (Box-folder 33.6)
  - Biochemistry and Biophysics Experimental Techniques, 1951-1961 (Box-folder 33.7)
  - Biochemistry and Biophysics Experimental Techniques, 1951-1961 (Box-folder 34.1)
  - Carbohydrate Metabolism, 1951-1960 (Box-folder 34.2)
  - Carbohydrate Metabolism, 1952-1960 (Box-folder 34.3)
  - Carbohydrate Metabolism, 1952-1961 (Box-folder 34.4)
  - Acetic Acid, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 34.5)
  - Amino Acids, 1949-1956 (Box-folder 34.6)
  - Histidine, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 34.7)
  - Leucine Isoleucine Valine, 1950-1955 (Box-folder 35.1)
  - Aspartic Serine Glycine Threonine, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 35.2)
  - Animals (General), 1941-1956 (Box-folder 35.3)
  - Animals (General), 1952-1961 (Box-folder 35.4)
  - Animals (General), 1953-1961 (Box-folder 35.5)
  - Acetic Acid Bacteria, 1954-1961 (Box-folder 35.6)
  - Aerobacters, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 35.7)
  - Bacillus Bacteria, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 35.8)
  - E. Coli Bacteria, 1951-1960 (Box-folder 36.1)
  - Pseudomonas Bacteria, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 36.2)
  - Streptomyces Bacteria, 1949-1960 (Box-folder 36.3)
  - Yeast, 1952-1961 (Box-folder 36.4)
  - Yeast, 1953-1959 (Box-folder 36.5)
  - Microorganisms (General), 1950-1959 (Box-folder 37.1)
  - Microorganisms (General), 1951-1958 (Box-folder 37.2)
  - Microorganisms (General), 1951-1960 (Box-folder 37.3)
  - Microorganisms (General), 1951-1961 (Box-folder 37.4)
  - Microorganisms (General), 1953-1961 (Box-folder 38.1)
  - Microorganisms (General), 1955-1959 (Box-folder 38.2)
  - Plants (General), 1926-1961 (Box-folder 38.3)
  - Plants (General), 1937-1960 (Box-folder 38.4)
  - Plants (General), 1951-1955 (Box-folder 38.5)
  - Plants (General), 1952-1961 (Box-folder 39.1)
  - Photosynthesis, 1951-1960 (Box-folder 39.2)
  - Photosynthesis, 1951-1960 (Box-folder 39.3)
  - Carbon Dating, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 39.4)
  - Carbon Dioxide, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 39.5)
  - Radiation Biology, 1955-1961 (Box-folder 39.6)
  - Radioactive Tracer Methodology, 1944-1961 (Box-folder 40.1)
  - Extraction of Uranium from Seawater, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 40.2)
  - Extraction of Uranium from Seawater, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 40.3)
  - Extraction of Uranium from Phosphate Ores, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 40.4)
  - Radiation Liability, 1958 (Box-folder 40.5)
  - Nuclear Reactor Regulation in California, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 40.6)
  - Nuclear Reactor Regulation in Oregon, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 40.7)
  - Nuclear Reactor Regulation in Washington, 1976 (Box-folder 40.8)
  - Oregon Department of Resource Management, 1976 (Box-folder 41.1)
  - Oregon Student Public Interest Research Group (OSPIRG), 1976 (Box-folder 41.2)
  - Oregonians Against the Ban on Nuclear Energy, 1976 (Box-folder 41.3)
  - Anti-Nuclear Campaigns, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 41.4)
  - "Energy Resources--How much, How Soon" Film, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 41.5)
  - "Red Alert" Film, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 41.6)
  - Miscellaneous Reprints, 1949-1955 (Box-folder 41.7)
  - Miscellaneous Reprints, 1950-1961 (Box-folder 41.8)
  - Miscellaneous Reprints, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 42.1)
  - Miscellaneous Reprints, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 42.2)